Register of the Joan Beecher Eichrodt collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Joan Beecher Eichrodt collection
1872-2002
2006C62
Hoover Institution Archives
33 manuscript boxes, 1 card file box, 11 oversize boxes (24.5 linear feet)
Sound recordings, transcripts and summaries of interviews, notes, reports, conference proceedings, newspapers, other printed matter, and photographs relating to nationalism and separatism in Chechnia and elsewhere in the Caucasus. Digital copies of selected items available.
Eichrodt, Joan Beecher, collector.
Access
Collection is open for research.
Use copies of some sound recordings in the collection are available for immediate access. To listen to other sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2006.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Chechen subject collection, Hoover Institution Archives
Kara-kys Dongikovna Arakchaa papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Paul B. Henze papers, Hoover Institution Archives
Biographical Note
1933 October 31 Born, Birmingham, Alabama
1959-1961 Senior Translator, Radio Liberty
1961-1966 Policy and Planning Coordinator, U.S. Division, Radio Liberty
1965 BA, Goddard College, Plainfield, VT
1968 MA, History, Columbia University. Thesis: "Orthodoxy, Autocracy, Nationality and Joseph de Maistre"
1975 PhD, History, Columbia University. Dissertation: "Anarchy and Culture: Dmitry Merezhkovsky and the Kairos"
1976-1983 Adjunct Professor, Western Connecticut State College
1977-1983 Columnist, Citizen News, New Fairfield, CT
1983-1984 Program Officer, Harriman Institute for Advanced Study of the Soviet Union, Columbia University
1985-1990s Senior Correspondent and Soviet Affairs Analyst, Voice of America
1994-1995 MacArthur Foundation Grant for Research and Writing
1994-1997 Conducted research and interviews in the Caucasus, primarily in Chechnia
2008 January 31 Died, New York
Scope and Content of Collection
The Joan Beecher Eichrodt collection consists of sound recordings, transcripts and summaries of interviews, notes, reports, conference proceedings, newspapers, other printed matter, and photographs relating to nationalism and separatism in Chechnia and elsewhere in the Caucasus.
As a Voice of America correspondent, Eichrodt made frequent trips to the Soviet Union to cover the Congress of People's Deputies (S"ezd narodnykh deputatov), a democratically elected assembly created by Mikhail Gorbachev in 1989. Through a series of interviews with Congress members, Eichrodt documented the attitudes of Russian officials toward Gorbachev's union treaty and the rights of autonomous republics, audiotapes of which can be found in the Russia subseries of the Sound Recordings series.
After the dissolution of the Soviet Union, Eichrodt was interested primarily in nationalist and separatist groups within the Russian Federation, particularly the North Caucasus. In 1994, she received a MacArthur grant to write a book on the history and contemporary politics of the North Caucasus, the proposal for which can be found in the Personal File.
From 1994 to 1996, Eichrodt used her grant to travel extensively in the Caucasus, interviewing hundreds of local government officials, citizens, and refugees on separatist movements and territorial conflicts. These taped interviews are in the Sound Recordings series and grouped by Caucasian republic. Included among Eichrodt's interviewees are Chechen presidents Dzhokhar Dudaev and Aslan Maskhadov, Ingushetian president Ruslan Aushev, opposition leader Zelimkhan Iandarbiev and public figure Ruslan Labazanov. Most of the interviews conducted in Chechnia are on domestic affairs from 1990 to 1997, although some relate to Stalin's 1944 deportations of Chechens and Ingush. The collection includes Interview Transcripts of selected tapes as well as Notebooks maintained by Eichrodt during her interviews and research trips.
In addition to the hundreds of recorded interviews, the bulk of the collection consists of Research Materials, Clippings and Newspapers related to Eichrodt's Voice of America reports, as well as her planned book on the Caucasus. Topics include history of the North Caucasian republics, the 1994-1996 war between Russia and Chechnia ethnic relations, and cross-border conflicts in the Caucasus, particularly between Ingushetia and Ossetia.
Chechni͡a (Russia)--History.; Caucasus, South--Politics and government--1991-; Nationalism--Russia (Federation)--Chechni͡a.; Nationalism--Caucasus, South.; Audiotapes.
- Personal File, 1990-1996 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Resumes, correspondence, and working files relating primarily to Eichrodt's MacArthur grant for research in the Caucasus. Maintained in Eichrodt's original order.
  - Resumes, circa 1995 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - MacArthur grant files, 1994-1996
    - Project description, 1994 (Box-folder 1: 2)
    - Project budget, 1994 (Box-folder 1: 3)
    - Bibliography, 1994 (Box-folder 1: 4)
    - Correspondence, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 1: 5)
    - Expense reports and receipts, 1994-1995 (Box-folder 1: 6-9)
    - Speech, circa 1994 (Box-folder 1: 10)
    - Trip summaries, 1995 (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - Contacts files, 1990, 1993, undated
    - General, undated (Box-folder 1: 12-13)
    - Caucasus, undated (Box-folder 1: 14)
    - Dagestan, undated (Box-folder 1: 15)
    - Latvia, 1990 (Box-folder 1: 16)
    - Russian Federation, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 17)
- Correspondence, 1993-1999 (Box 1)
  Arrangement note
  In alphabetical order by correspondent.
  - Akaev, Vakhit, 1997 October 22 (Box-folder 1: 18)
  - Balzer, Harley, 1995 February 27 (Box-folder 1: 19)
  - Colarusso, John, 1994 March 16 (Box-folder 1: 20)
  - Cowan, Geoffrey, 1996 May 9 (Box-folder 1: 21)
  - Furman, Sasha, 1990s (Box-folder 1: 22)
  - Khadzhiev, Salambek, 1995 June 23 (Box-folder 1: 23)
  - Kolt, George, 1995 March 1 (Box-folder 1: 24)
  - Maskhadov, Aslan, 1998 (Box-folder 1: 25)
  - Mezhdunarodnaia cherkesskaia assotsiatsiia, 1993 (Box-folder 1: 26)
  - Nazmutdinov, Mirgaziian Mirgazdinovich, 1997 February 21 (Box-folder 1: 27)
  - Putin, Vladimir, 1999 November (Box-folder 1: 28)
    Open letter in response to Putin's editorial in The New York Times.
  - Romash, Aleksandr, 1995 October 27 (Box-folder 1: 29)
  - Teziev, Oleg, after 1991 (Box-folder 1: 30)
- Voice of America Files, 1985-1994 (Boxes 1-2)
  Transcripts, notes, and office files from Eichrodt's tenure at the Voice of America. Grouped by format and ordered chronologically.
  - Radio transcripts, 1985-1994
    Reports filed by Eichrodt relating primarily to the war in Afghanistan, U.S.-Soviet relations, Russian domestic politics, and the Caucasus.
    - 1985 December (Box-folder 1: 31)
    - 1986
      - January-June (Box-folder 1: 32-35)
      - July-September (Box-folder 1: 36-38)
      - October-December (Box-folder 2: 1-4)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 2: 5-8)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 2: 9)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 2: 10)
    - 1990 (Box-folder 2: 11)
    - 1991 (Box-folder 2: 12-13)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 2: 14)
    - 1993 (Box-folder 2: 15)
    - 1994 (Box-folder 2: 16-17)
  - Correspondents' reports, 1985 (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - Notes, 1994 September (Box-folder 2: 19)
  - Proposals for Development Office, 1994 (Box-folder 2: 20)
- Interview Transcripts, 1990-1997 (Boxes 3-7)
  Full and partial transcripts from interviews conducted by Eichrodt and related materials. Maintained in Eichrodt's original order: by geographical location and then alphabetically by surname.
  - Abkhazia, 1993-1994
    - Achba, Zurab, 1993 August 28 (Box-folder 3: 1)
    - Akaba, Natella, 1993 August (Box-folder 3: 2)
    - Akhba, [?], 1993 October 22 (Box-folder 3: 3)
    - Goble, Paul, 1993 October 22, 1994 February 8 (Box-folder 3: 4)
    - Gumba, Valeriĭ, 1993 October 24 (Box-folder 3: 5)
    - Henze, Paul, 1994 January 28 (Box-folder 3: 6)
    - Igrunov, Viacheslav, 1994 February 7 (Box-folder 3: 7)
    - Loginov, Viktor Anatolévich, 1993 August 29 (Box-folder 3: 8)
    - Ochs, Michael, 1994 January 28, undated (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - Ochs, Michael and Paul Henze, undated (Box-folder 3: 10)
    - Shamba, Sergeĭ, 1993 October 23 (Box-folder 3: 11)
    - Slider, Darryl, 1993 October 22 (Box-folder 3: 12)
    - Related documents, 1993
      - "Memorandum of Understanding between the Georgian and Abkhaz Sides at the Negotiations in Geneva,", 1993 December 1 (Box-folder 3: 13)
      - "Problemy vyvoda gruzinskikh voĭsk iz Abkhazii,", 1993 June 7 (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - Chechnia, 1991, 1993-1996
    - Akhmadov, Iavus Zaĭndievich, 1994 November 3 and December 8-9 (Box-folder 3: 15)
    - Aliroev, Isa, 1994 November 3-4 (Box-folder 3: 16)
    - Arsanov, Akhmed, 1995 (Box-folder 3: 17)
    - Aslakhanov, Aslambek, 1991, 1994-1996
      - 1991 October 13 (Box-folder 3: 18)
      - 1994 November 28 (Box-folder 3: 19)
      - 1995 January 5 (Box-folder 3: 20)
      - 1996 March 31 (Box-folder 3: 21)
    - Avturkhanov, Umar, 1994 October (Box-folder 3: 22)
    - Baĭsultanov, Dadash, 1993 May 31 (Box-folder 3: 23)
    - Beno, Shamil', 1995 May 5 (Box-folder 3: 24)
    - Bugaev, Abdula, 1994 October 29 and December 3 (Box-folder 3: 25)
    - Dudaev, Dzhokhar, 1992, 1994
      - 1992 January and September 15 (Box-folder 3: 26)
      - 1994 December (Box-folder 3: 27)
        Press conference
    - El'murzaev, Iusup, 1994 November (Box-folder 3: 28)
    - Eskiev, Ali, 1992 January (Box-folder 3: 29)
    - Gakaev, Gabriil, 1994 September (Box-folder 3: 30)
    - Gantamirov, Bislan, 1993 June 2, 1995 May 29 (Box-folder 3: 31-32)
    - Geliskhanov, Sultan, 1994 October (Box-folder 3: 33)
    - Iandarbiev, Zelimkhan, 1994 November 30 (Box-folder 3: 34)
      Includes a poem.
    - Kadyrov, Akhmed-Khadzhi, 1995 May 9 (Box-folder 3: 35)
    - Karaev, Ruslan, 1995 June 21 (Box-folder 3: 36)
    - Kariev, [?], undated (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - Khadzhiev, Salambek, 1994-1996, undated
      - 1994 December 6 (Box-folder 4: 2)
      - 1995 December 12, 1996 March (Box-folder 4: 3)
      - undated (Box-folder 4: 4)
    - Khasbulatov, Ruslan, 1992, 1994, 1996
      - 1992 April 13 (Box-folder 4: 5)
      - 1994 October (Box-folder 4: 6)
      - 1994 October 29, 1996 March 31 (Box-folder 4: 7)
    - Khatueva, Raia, 1994 October (Box-folder 4: 8)
    - Labazanov, Magomed, 1996 February 22 (Box-folder 4: 9)
    - Labazanov, Ruslan, 1995 February (Box-folder 4: 10)
    - Madiev, Ruslan, 1995 February (Box-folder 4: 11)
    - Martagov, Ruslan, 1994 December (Box-folder 4: 12)
    - Meduev, Sultan, 1995 January 18 (Box-folder 4: 13)
    - Muzaev, Timur, 1993 June 26 (Box-folder 4: 14)
    - Satyrov, Umali, 1994 October (Box-folder 4: 15)
    - Soslambekov, Iusup, undated (Box-folder 4: 16)
    - Sumtsov, [?], undated (Box-folder 4: 17)
    - Umkhaev, Lecha, 1993 May 26, 1995 May 1 (Box-folder 4: 18-19)
    - Zakriev, Ruslan, 1994 October 24 (Box-folder 4: 20)
    - [?], Lara, 1995 February (Box-folder 4: 21)
    - Group interviews, 1991, 1993-1995
      - Bena-Iurt, 1994 December 11 (Box-folder 4: 22)
      - Bus trip to Vedeno, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 23)
      - Chechen deputies, 1993 May (Box-folder 4: 24)
      - Chechen Opposition Press Center, 1994 October 2 (Box-folder 4: 25)
      - Chechen Women's Committee, 1994 October (Box-folder 4: 26)
      - Diaspora conference, 1994 September (Box-folder 4: 27)
      - Deportation accounts, 1995 (Box-folder 4: 28)
      - Dudaev, Dzhokhar, Movladi Udugov and others, 1991 (Box-folder 4: 29)
        From the first Chechen Congress.
      - Ialkharoĭ villagers, 1995 May (Box-folder 4: 30)
      - Khasan, 1994 December 19 (Box-folder 4: 31)
      - Priemnaia and Znamenskoe, 1994 October (Box-folder 4: 32)
      - Shatoĭ, undated (Box-folder 4: 33)
      - Sleptsovsk refugees, 1995 January (Box-folder 5: 1-2)
      - Soldiers' mothers, 1995 January 27 (Box-folder 5: 3)
      - Theater Square, 1993 May (Box-folder 5: 4)
      - Vedeno, 1995 (Box-folder 5: 5)
    - Related documents, 1991, 1994-1995, undated
      - Chechen leader dossiers, circa 1994 (Box-folder 5: 6)
      - "Chechenskiĭ krizis: etnosotsial'nye i kul'turnye aspekty," roundtable, 1995 January (Box-folder 5: 7-8)
      - "Chechentsy: istoriko-geograficheskiĭ i statistiko-ekonomicheskiĭ ocherk," Terskiĭ sbornik, 1893 (Box-folder 5: 9)
        Photocopy with notes
      - Chechnia: vzgliad iznutri, Iusup Soslambekov, 1995 (Box-folder 5: 10-11)
      - Diaspora Congress draft resolution, 1994 September (Box-folder 5: 12)
      - Dzhokhar Dudaev interview notes, 1991 October-November (Box-folder 5: 13)
      - "Message to the Russian people by Sheikh Dzhamo,", undated (Box-folder 5: 14)
      - "Mir luchshe pobedy," Aslambek Aslakhanov, undated (Box-folder 5: 15)
      - Statement to the Chechen people by Ruslan Zakriev, undated (Box-folder 5: 16)
      - Television transcript, 1994 December 4 (Box-folder 5: 17)
      - Vozrozhdenie notes, 1994 July-September (Box-folder 5: 18)
  - Dagestan, 1992
    - Abduragimov, Gadzhi Aslanovich, 1992 (Box-folder 5: 19)
    - Dadash, 1992 January (Box-folder 5: 20)
    - Lezgians, 1992 July 30 (Box-folder 5: 21)
    - Meĭlanov, Vazif and Eduard Urazaev, 1992 (Box-folder 5: 22)
  - Ingushetia, 1993-1995
    - Agapov, Boris, 1993 January (Box-folder 5: 23)
    - Alikhanova, Liudmila, 1995 January 20 (Box-folder 5: 24)
    - Aushev, Ruslan, 1993 January, 1995 January (Box-folder 5: 25)
    - Gorokhov, Eduard, 1995 January (Box-folder 6: 1)
    - Kostoev, Issa, 1993 February 9 (Box-folder 6: 2)
    - Mutaliev, Timurlan, undated (Box-folder 6: 3)
    - Pliev, Mark, undated (Box-folder 6: 4)
    - Refugees, 1993, 1995, undated (Box-folder 6: 5-8)
    - Interview fragment, undated (Box-folder 6: 9)
    - Related documents, 1993
    - Message to the Constitutional Court of the Russian Federation from the Moscow Committee on the Situation in Ingushetia, 1993 December (Box-folder 6: 10)
    - Resolution of the Extraordinary Congress of the People of Ingushetia, 1992 December 5 (Box-folder 6: 11)
    - Speech at the Congress of Repressed Minorities, 1993 May 21 (Box-folder 6: 12)
  - Moldova, 1997
    - Socor, Vladimir, 1997 April 7 (Box-folder 6: 13)
  - Nogai Congresses, 1989, 1990, 1994 (Box-folder 6: 14-16)
    Includes transcripts, addresses, decrees and resolutions.
  - North Caucasus, 1992-1994, undated
    - Ibragimbeĭli, Khadzhi-Murat, 1992 September (Box-folder 6: 17)
    - Shakhraĭ, Sergeĭ, 1994 October (Box-folder 6: 18)
    - Shanibov, Iuriĭ, undated (Box-folder 6: 19)
    - Volunteers in the Abkhaz War, undated (Box-folder 6: 20)
    - Related documents, 1993, undated
      - Congress of Repressed Minorities, 1993 May 17-21 (Box-folder 6: 21)
      - Notes, undated (Box-folder 6: 22)
  - Ossetia, 1992-1993, 1995
    - Chochiev, Alan, 1993 March 24 (Box-folder 6: 23)
    - Kuzmiev, [?], 1995 (Box-folder 6: 24)
    - Refugees, 1993 February 2 (Box-folder 6: 25)
    - Tsagolov, Kim, undated (Box-folder 7: 1)
    - Tsomaev, Astemir, 1992 (Box-folder 7: 2-4)
  - Russian Soviet Federative Socialist Republic (RSFSR) and Russian Federation, 1990-1991, 1993
    - Bicheldeĭ, Kaadyr-ool Alekseevich, 1991 May (Box-folder 7: 5)
    - Kaledin, Vasiliĭ Ivanovich and Vasiliĭ Krasuli, 1993 April (Box-folder 7: 6)
    - Medvedev, Nikolaĭ, undated (Box-folder 7: 7)
    - Osipov, Nikolaĭ, 1990 October 25 (Box-folder 7: 8)
    - Ruble, Blair, 1993 November 5 (Box-folder 7: 9)
    - Salmin, Alekseĭ, 1991 June (Box-folder 7: 10)
    - Travkin, Nikolaĭ, undated (Box-folder 7: 11)
    - Zubov, Andrei Borisovich and Aleksei Salmin, undated (Box-folder 7: 12)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box-folder 7: 13)
    - Radio script, 1991 March 27 (Box-folder 7: 14)
  - S"ezd narodov Vostoka, circa 1990, undated
    - Bashkir and Meskhetian Turk, circa 1990 (Box-folder 7: 15)
    - Khamzin, Mirkhan, undated (Box-folder 7: 16)
    - Nogais, undated (Box-folder 7: 17)
    - Related documents, 1990, undated
      - Conference proceedings, 1990 (Box-folder 7: 18-23)
      - Deklaratsiia prav narodov Vostoka, 1990 September 27 (Box-folder 7: 24)
      - Message from the Turkish, Farsi, and Caucasian Peoples, undated (Box-folder 7: 25)
- Research Materials, 1872-2002 (Boxes 8-23)
  Clippings, printed matter, reports, circulated material, and published and unpublished writings by others used by Eichrodt for her Voice of America reports and planned book on the Caucasus. Maintained in Eichrodt's original subject designations and arranged alphabetically by subject or title.
  - Abkhazia, 1992-1993, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 8: 1-19)
  - Adygea, 1993 (Box-folder 8: 20)
  - Alani, 1973, undated (Box-folder 8: 21)
  - Anarcho-syndicalists, 1990 July, undated (Box-folder 8: 22)
  - Armenia, 1988 (Box-folder 8: 23)
  - Autonomy and independence movements, 1990-1992
    - General, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 9: 1-7)
    - Iakutiia (Sakha), 1990-1991 (Box-folder 9: 8)
    - Kalmyks, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 9: 9)
    - Karelia, 1990 (Box-folder 9: 10)
  - Biographical materials on Aleksandr Romash, Movladi Udugov and Akhmed Zakaev, after 1996 (Box-folder 9: 11)
  - Caspian oil and gas, 1996-1998 (Box-folder 9: 12-16)
  - Caucasus, general, 1995-1996, undated (Box-folder 9: 17-18)
  - Central Asia, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 9: 19)
  - Chechnia, 1990-1999
    - Chechenskiĭ obshchenatsional'nyĭ s"ezd, 1990-1991 (Box-folder 9: 20)
    - Circulated material, 1993 (Box-folder 9: 21)
    - Clippings, 1994 (Box-folder 9: 22)
    - Correspondence, Congressman Frank Wolf with Al Gore and Bill Clinton, photocopies, 1992 (Box-folder 9: 23)
    - Country reports, undated (Box-folder 9: 24)
    - Flyers and open letters, 1994-1996, undated (Box-folder 9: 25)
    - Foreign Broadcast Information Service reports, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 10: 1-3)
    - Hearing on Chechnia crimes, undated (Box-folder 10: 4)
      Fragment
    - Internet printouts, 1996-1999 (Box-folder 10: 5-10, 11: 1-3)
    - Khartiia mira i soglasiia v Chechenskoĭ respublike, 1995 April 21 (Box-folder 11: 4)
    - "Kto est' kto v Chechne i vokrug nee,", circa 1996 (Box-folder 11: 5)
    - Printed matter, 1994, 1996, undated (Box-folder 11: 6)
      Includes book excerpt on folk songs and two serial issues: Zhenskiĭ zhurnal Chechenskoĭ Respubliki and Vainakh segodnia.
    - Radio Free Europe reports, 1994 (Box-folder 11: 7)
    - Resolution, Groznenskoe gorodskoe sobranie, 1993 April 19 (Box-folder 11: 8)
    - "Rezhim Dudaeva,", circa 1994 (Box-folder 11: 9)
    - Stenogramma zasedaniia Komissii po issledovaniiu prichin i obstoiatel'stv vozniknoveniia krizisnoĭ situatsii v Chechenskoĭ Respublike, circa 1994 (Box-folder 11: 10)
  - Cossacks, 1991-1993, undated (Box-folder 11: 11-19)
    Includes photograph of seven Cossack men in national dress.
  - Dagestan, 1990-1993, 1997-1999, undated
    - Clippings and internet printouts, 1990-1993, 1997-1999 (Box-folder 11: 20-27)
    - Printed matter and reports, 1990, 1993, undated (Box-folder 12: 1-4)
  - Ethnic conflict, 1991, 1993-1995, undated (Box-folder 12: 5-7)
  - Foreign Broadcast Information Service (FBIS) reports, 1995 February-April (Box-folder 12: 8-10)
  - Georgia, 1991-1994 (Box-folder 12: 11-20)
    Includes correspondence relating to repression of journalists in Georgia.
  - Information agency briefings and reports, 1989-1990
    - DS-Inform, 1990 (Box-folder 12: 21-22)
    - Interfax (Joint Telefax publication of Radio Moscow and Soviet-Franco-Italian Venture "Interquadro"), circa 1990 (Box-folder 12: 23)
    - Moskovskoe biuro informatsionnogo obmena (M-BIO), 1989-1990
      - Khronika, 1989 (Box-folder 12: 24)
      - Novyĭ khronograf, 1990 (Box-folder 12: 25)
      - Sluzhba ezhednevnykh novosteĭ, 1990 (Box-folder 13: 1-3)
    - Profsoiuz nezavisimykh zhurnalistov SSSR, 1990 (Box-folder 13: 4-6)
    - Severo-Zapad, 1989 (Box-folder 13: 7)
    - Sibirskoe informatsionnoe agentstvo, 1989 (Box-folder 13: 8)
  - Ingushetia, 1991-1993, 1996 (Box-folder 13: 9-20)
  - Kabardino-Balkariia, 1992-1994, undated (Box-folder 13: 21-27)
  - Karachay-Cherkessia, 1991-1993, undated (Box-folder 14: 1-3)
  - Kennan Institute, 1995 (Box-folder 14: 4)
  - Krasnodarskiĭ kraĭ (Kuban), circa 1996 (Box-folder 14: 5-7)
  - Moldova and the Dniester Moldovan Republic, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 14: 8)
  - Nagorno-Karabakh, 1993, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 14: 9-13)
  - Natsional'no-patrioticheskiĭ front (NPF) "Pamiat',", 1987, 1990 (Box-folder 14: 14)
  - Nogai Congress, 1990 (Box-folder 14: 15)
  - North Ossetia, 1992-1994, 1997-1998
    Relates primarily to conflict with Ingushetia.
    - Clippings, 1992 (Box-folder 14: 16)
    - Congress of Ossetian People, 1993 (Box-folder 14: 17)
    - "Etnopoliticheskaia situatsiia na Severnom Kavkaze," Rossiiskaia akademiia nauk (RAN), 1993 (Box-folder 14: 18)
    - Government documents, 1994 (Box-folder 14: 19)
    - Internet printouts, 1997-1998 (Box-folder 14: 20-21)
    - Pamphlets on Ingush violence against Ossetians, 1992 (Box-folder 14: 22)
    - Prigorodnyĭ raĭon, 1992 (Box-folder 15: 1)
    - Violence against Ingush, 1993 (Box-folder 15: 2)
  - Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE), 1996-1997 (Box-folder 15: 3)
  - Political parties and organizations, 1989-1993 (Box-folder 15: 4-15)
    Includes short profiles of political groups.
  - REESWeb: Russian and East European Studies Internet Resources, 1996 (Box-folder 15: 16)
  - Russian Federation, 1992-1998
    - Constitution, 1992 (Box-folder 15: 17)
    - Duma bulletins and reports, 1993-1995 (Box-folder 15: 18-25)
    - General, 1992-1998 (Box-folder 16: 1-15)
    - Government decrees on Chechnia, Ingushetia and Ossetia, 1992, 1994-1996 (Box-folder 16: 16-17)
    - Relations with republics, 1992-1993 (Box-folder 16: 18-19)
    - Presidential elections, 1996 (Box-folder 16: 20-22)
  - Russian Movement for Chechnia Independence, 1996 (Box-folder 17: 1)
    Includes correspondence and photograph of protestors.
  - Soiuz Musul'man Rossii, 1995 September 1-3 (Box-folder 17: 2)
  - South Ossetia, 1992-1997 (Box-folder 17: 3-6)
  - Soviet Union, 1985-1991
    - Afghanistan, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 17: 7-24)
    - Autonomy and independence movements, 1990 (Box-folder 17: 25)
    - Communist Party, 1987-1991 (Box-folder 17: 26-30)
    - Defense, circa 1986 (Box-folder 17: 31-32)
    - Democratic opposition, 1991 (Box-folder 18: 1-2)
    - Economics, 1985-1987, undated (Box-folder 18: 3-15)
    - Elections in Lithuania, 1998-1990 (Box-folder 18: 16)
    - Ethnopolitics, 1991 (Box-folder 18: 17)
    - Federation agreement, 1990 (Box-folder 18: 18)
    - Gorbachev, Mikhail, 1990 (Box-folder 18: 19-20)
    - Heritage Foundation, 1991 (Box-folder 18: 21)
    - Human rights, 1986-1987
      - General, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 18: 22-27)
      - Helsinki Act, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 18: 28-30)
      - Jewish emigration, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 18: 31)
      - Khodorovich, Sergeĭ, 1987 January 30 (Box-folder 18: 32)
      - Koriagin, Anatoliĭ Ivanovich, 1987 (Box-folder 19: 1)
      - Marchenko, Anatoliĭ, 1986 (Box-folder 19: 2)
      - Psychiatric abuses, 1987 (Box-folder 19: 3)
      - Ratushinskaia, Irina, 1986 (Box-folder 19: 4)
      - Refuseniks, 1987 (Box-folder 19: 5)
      - Reykjavik meeting, 1986 (Box-folder 19: 6)
      - Sakharov, Andreĭ, 1986-1987 (Box-folder 19: 7)